<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="http://www.positiverevolution.com.au/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://www.positiverevolution.com.au/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://www.positiverevolution.com.au/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-12-30T00:33:19+00:00</updated><id>http://www.positiverevolution.com.au//</id><title type="html">Positive Revolution</title><subtitle>Positive Revolution provides outsourced company culture development. We work with companies and organisations to provide the people balance ensuring they are happy, healthy and love working for the organisations they are with. Located in Cairns, Queensland, we travel throughout Australia.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The 4 M’s for making headway business.</title><link href="http://www.positiverevolution.com.au/blog/the-4-ms-for-making-headway-business/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The 4 M’s for making headway business." /><published>2016-12-09T10:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-12-09T10:20:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.positiverevolution.com.au/blog/the-4-ms-for-making-headway-business</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.positiverevolution.com.au/blog/the-4-ms-for-making-headway-business/">&lt;p&gt;These are not new and they have been around for some time now.  Rehashing these at times is good for every business owner from macro business to medium business owners, even perhaps big business as well.  After having a conversation with a business associate recently it became aware that some business professionals are still unaware of these points.  This prompted me to again hit the refresh button on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order these are Mindset, Motivation, Match, and Media/Market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mindset&lt;/strong&gt; – When working with clients I often find myself asking about their mindset for business.  I ask them if they see their business in their mind in 10 years’ time.  If this is not something you can visualise then I am concerned they don’t have the determination and persistence to make the sacrifices needed to ensure the longevity of the business.  I begin by getting the business professionals to ensure they are in the right industry and when I say this, I mean do they have the passion for what they are doing or is it a means to get money to fund a lifestyle they believe they want.  If the first is not the case, then I recommend they find something more aligned with their passion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Motivation&lt;/strong&gt; – Ask yourself if you’re in business, are you motivated every day to want to get up and do what you do.  I know that not everyone every day is bursting out of their skin to bounce out of bed and begin the grey matter swirling with possibilities of what they can do next to provide even more value to their customers and clients.  We all have our ups and downs and anyone who tells you different is a liar.  You want to wake up every day with a though of how can I be of better service today.  Be it by changing a way you serve your customers or a change in product which will provide even more benefit to your clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Match&lt;/strong&gt; – This is an important one because not everyone is going to want what you provide.  The idea is to work out who is going to be your match.  Why do you do what you do?  Like Simon Sinek has written about “Start with Why” then go and find the people who are a match and believe what you believe about your product or service.  Don’t try to be a match for everyone because you will waste valuable time and resources chopping and changing to be someone you aren’t to please people who don’t believe what you believe.  Dig deep and really think about who would be the best match for you and then go and complete the last M.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Media/Market&lt;/strong&gt; – Now you are determined you are in the right business and are dedicated to being in it for the long run.  You wake up majority of the time excited by the possibility of being able to better serve the people who are your clients and are working out how to do it even better.  You know what your match is and you are focused on targeting them because they are looking for the solution you provide.  Finally, how are you going to reach them?  Is it through the TV, Radio, newspaper, online blogging, viral videos or even holding demonstrations or speaking engagements.  Remember though which ever method you choose make sure you test and measure.  This way, in time you will find out what is working and what is not working for you.  When you know, what is working for you, focus your energy and resources there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you know the 4 M’s of business if you didn’t know them before or have just had a refresher.  Action is the key to any type of success so plan, execute and reap the rewards, though always remember you will have ups and you will have downs.\
Stay strong in the downs and don’t let the ups go to your head!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forever humbled G.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">These are not new and they have been around for some time now.  Rehashing these at times is good for every business owner from macro business to medium business owners, even perhaps big business as well.  After having a conversation with a business associate recently it became aware that some business professionals are still unaware of these points.  This prompted me to again hit the refresh button on them.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.positiverevolution.com.au/uploads/NLP%202.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Business: What a game!</title><link href="http://www.positiverevolution.com.au/blog/business-what-a-game/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Business: What a game!" /><published>2016-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.positiverevolution.com.au/blog/business-what-a-game</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.positiverevolution.com.au/blog/business-what-a-game/">&lt;p&gt;Is this true? (Jack Stack certainly thinks so!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should it be considered as one?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you ever hear business professional using terms like “having a win”, “made a bad play” or even “dropped the ball” etc. Certainly sounds like a game to me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, how do you get to know how to play a game?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, you learn the rules, don’t you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many business owners who are currently running businesses without knowing how to play the game by the rules. How do I know! By having conversations with business owners weekly in regards to how successful their businesses are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I keep finding is they’re not playing by the rules to become successful. They’re playing by some, if not most of the rules, though they don’t have all the rules to ensure they are successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK, so how do you become successful?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first point in any game is to decide how you will measure success, as success is different for every person. So firstly what is your version of success for now in your profession. I say for now because as you achieve success, your version of success will also change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you know what success is for you, you then need to be brutally honest with yourself and work out where you are currently in comparison to your successful state. &lt;strong&gt;Don’t start playing the game until you figure this out in detail!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing where you are and where you want to be are the makings for your success. The next rule of the game is doing a gap analysis of what you have in place, what you need to have in place and what is in place that shouldn’t even be there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of the end result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you do for your customers and clients?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the KIS model {Keep It Simple} breakdown the fundamentals for your business. At the core, what is it you do for your customers?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance – if you provide an end product which you build. E.g. Shed, house, Boat, caravan etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You take manufactured materials and use them by shaping, bending and joining for the end result. So the job is to provide great service, in a timely manner of the highest quality which you and your team can produce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you currently providing the highest quality product with the best customer service? If not, then the question is, what’s missing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember: &lt;strong&gt;The GAME never ends!&lt;/strong&gt; Just when you think you have it all figured out and you’re doing everything right, something will change which will have you going over your processes again. The businesses who don’t continuously develop and change are no longer around. (Take Blockbuster for instance.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. Ensure you continue on an ongoing cycle of learning and business development to stay on the crest of the success wave.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Is this true? (Jack Stack certainly thinks so!)</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.positiverevolution.com.au/uploads/business-what-a-game.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Developing Culture through beliefs.</title><link href="http://www.positiverevolution.com.au/blog/developing-culture-through-beliefs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Developing Culture through beliefs." /><published>2016-10-01T12:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-10-01T12:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.positiverevolution.com.au/blog/developing-culture-through-beliefs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.positiverevolution.com.au/blog/developing-culture-through-beliefs/">&lt;p&gt;In the last blog post we discussed vision, mission and values to ensure you began designing the kind of culture you want to have in your organisation. Every step of this process is as important as the last. We will be required to ensure we have ongoing development in all areas, because things do change on a continuous basis. The only thing you can be certain about in this world is that it will constantly change. Just when you think you have it figured out, it will change again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post we are going to take a look at the beliefs within the organisation and how it contributes to the culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•   What do you believe about the work you do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•   Is it a waste of time, because it really isn’t that important?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•   Do you believe that people won’t change, so what is the point?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•   Do you believe that everyone is open to learn new experiences given the time and right incentives?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start off with I want to ask you what you think a belief is?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The popular definition of a belief is it’s a “Convenient assumption about the way the world is.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if a belief is just a convenient assumption, then how easy would it be to change our beliefs!  Think of a belief as a tall sky scraper (because it has taken many years to build your beliefs), and the foundations of it are the reasons we have to put in place to hold the belief to be true (Some of the foundations are deep because you have spent years developing reasons for the beliefs to be true).  What happens when we begin to question the reasons of a particular belief and figure out the reasons really can’t support that belief any longer?  Then your sky scraper begins to sway and shake, and eventually it will come down because without reasons your beliefs can’t stand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the test is making up a new beliefs and installing them, because if you take something away you must replace it with another or the same belief will be pulled back in to fill the void.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is up to the leaders in the organisation to assist the staff with changing their beliefs for the benefit of the organisation.  As an example, it is helpful to change the beliefs of salespeople who has limiting beliefs around how much money they can make.  It is also about assisting admin staff to believe that being able to communicate the needs of the staff to upper management so things can get better.  A great belief in this instance for an organisation would be open communication is the key to success.  It would really change the way everyone in the company communicated.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">In the last blog post we discussed vision, mission and values to ensure you began designing the kind of culture you want to have in your organisation. Every step of this process is as important as the last. We will be required to ensure we have ongoing development in all areas, because things do change on a continuous basis. The only thing you can be certain about in this world is that it will constantly change. Just when you think you have it figured out, it will change again.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.positiverevolution.com.au/uploads/Culture%20mot.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Do you lack employee engagement?</title><link href="http://www.positiverevolution.com.au/blog/do-you-lack-employee-engagement/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Do you lack employee engagement?" /><published>2016-09-01T12:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-09-01T12:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.positiverevolution.com.au/blog/do-you-lack-employee-engagement</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.positiverevolution.com.au/blog/do-you-lack-employee-engagement/">&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest issues that I find SME businesses are facing today is that they lack employee engagement.  So how to solve the problem and really get your employees treating the business as seriously as you do?
In this article, I will begin to set a foundation for employee engagement, starting with simple but very effective ways of getting your employees more engaged in your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 1.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conduct regular meetings&lt;/strong&gt; – Now, the following steps should be on the agenda in your next meeting.  What, you are not having meetings?  Then how is the information being shared around to the staff?  Where is the chance to come up with new ideas? Again I am reminded of businesses that I have worked with - they begin to have meetings, then because of the perpetual idea of lack of time, they stop doing them.  Conducting regular meetings is a vital step for every business.  It defines what people are doing from week to week and allows for everyone to brainstorm problems that a staff member may be facing.  It also allows for sharing ideas on how and where the business should be going.  Now, I know that for the last one, it should be up to the business leader to make the decisions in relation to the direction of the business, so I ask you to hear me out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For any high performing business, you get ideas from anywhere you can, and your employees are the ones on the ground doing the work, finding out the new ways of doing things in the marketplace.  They are the ones discovering new products, services and systems that are out there, and it’s always better to have many heads looking into things and getting a feel for the variety of change and challenges that may be coming. This way you will have an early indication of how the marketplace is changing for your business.  If your salesperson is out there having conversations and finds out there is a competitor’s new product being shown around that you don’t know about, do you just expect your salesperson to come back and say, “Hey, the competition is changing direction with a new product.  Is it something we should at least have a look at?”  Or are they forgetting about it when they walk out the door and don’t remember to tell you until the competitor has snuck in and taken business that could have been yours if only you knew about it sooner!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a million examples I could give in regards to why you will want to be having weekly meetings, though I do want to share that you should have a structured agenda to follow to make these meetings most effective.  A great place to start is by reading Edward De Bono’s book, Six Thinking Hats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 2.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create a vision statement&lt;/strong&gt; – Now, I know what is going through your mind - not another article telling me how important a vision statement is to a business.  We wouldn’t be saying it if it wasn’t important!  I have been working with a fair few businesses lately who have in upward of 5 or more staff and still lack the simplest drivers of a business.  If you don’t know where you are going, what are your staff working for?  Just so they can have a job and make you a little money.  Come on!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This, I think is where most SME businesses are currently lacking and, if they do have a vision statement, they have to go and look it up to tell me what it is.  How many of you that do have a vision statement actually engage the employees when you write it?  I believe in starting out with an idea and then taking it to your team to expand on it, but more importantly get them to begin to engage in what it will be like to work for a company that has such a vision and especially one that is including them in the writing of one.  Make it big and worthwhile, something the whole team requires to get behind to ensure they can work together to achieve it.  Put some measures (KPIs) in place as to how you will get there, and if you do achieve the vision, guess what?  It is time to set another one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 3.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create the mission&lt;/strong&gt; – Yes, again you are hearing it.  It is because it is so important that after setting a vision statement, you need to know how you are going to get there!  The mission statement is the HOW.  Again include your employees because these are the people who will be assisting you in realising the vision.  You want them to be included as to how you will all get there.  Believe it or not, it is normally the staff that come up with the best ideas, not the leaders or CEO.  This is again another way of getting the whole team engaged and it will create excitement in the business, as everyone has something to aim for, as well as some standards they will want to uphold.  Every weekly meeting should start out with the vision and mission statements and how you are tracking on achieving them.  Remember, a plane is off course 99% of the time on its way to the destination.  The pilot is making consistent checks and adjustments to ensure they get there.  This is the same for business.  As the environment is constantly changing, you need to be making consistent checks and adjustments to ensure you get to the vision you set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 4.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set business values&lt;/strong&gt; – These should be non-negotiable for every business.  Again ensure you engage your staff when setting the company values, because if the staff don’t collectively agree, how can you keep them accountable for ensuring the business sticks to the values that are set?  Employees are not just going to have the same values as the business owner and nor do they have to, though they should all agree on the values they uphold as part of the team.  When making these values, you need to stress the importance of them and be able to live up to them yourself.  There has to be a “We are all in this together” attitude.  Don’t be put out when an employee fronts you for not sticking to the values you have all agreed to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 5.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Come up with a tag line&lt;/strong&gt; – Every great business has a tag line.  Again include your employees - are you starting to see a theme emerging here?  The best way to engage the staff in your business is to give them a say in what happens.  Even though as the leader or CEO you still will have the final say, you may be surprised how much the employees enjoy the feeling of being an integral part of the company.  Be funky, catchy and enjoy the process, but also ensure it relates to the business.  Maybe even run an “in-house” bonus for the best tag line.  Think of all the big companies.  How did they get so big and what are their tag lines?  Test your knowledge – Coca Cola - ?  Stihl - ?  Subway - ?  How did you go?  Did you get any of them? Now go and engage your team to come up with a great tag line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you complete these steps to begin with, then you will start to see a difference with your employees and their level of engagement in your business.  It is all about making your staff feel they are part of the business, not just a number or a position.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">One of the biggest issues that I find SME businesses are facing today is that they lack employee engagement.  So how to solve the problem and really get your employees treating the business as seriously as you do?
In this article, I will begin to set a foundation for employee engagement, starting with simple but very effective ways of getting your employees more engaged in your business.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://www.positiverevolution.com.au/uploads/Lack.png" /></entry></feed>
